# Jacob Herper

# **Front-End Developer**

As a passionate front-end developer, I create amazing websites and web apps to make the internet a better place. I am an advocate for web performance and accessibility as well as a JAMstack enthusiast with experience in serverless technologies.

jacob@herper.uk

07535 822221

herper.io

linkedin.com/in/jacobherper

github.com/jakeherp

twitter.com/jakeherp

# **Work Experience**

#### 01/2019 - present

#### Front End Developer, Raconteur Media

- Built and maintained internal websites using React (Next.js and Gatsby) with GraphQL and WordPress as a data source
- Extended internal front-end component library in React with Styled Components
- Built animated chart library for a large B2B client using ZingCharts, JavaScript and Gulp as a build tool

# London, UK

## 12/2017 - 01/2019

# Front End Developer, The Specialist Works

- Designed and built the new global agency website with WordPress, combining 6 legacy websites into just one
- Coded PHP and JavaScript-based WordPress plugin for an energy provider in the UK
- Developed and maintained PWA for conference registration and on-site live updates for attendees.

#### London, UK

#### 01/2009 - present

#### Founder & Full Stack Developer, Creativ Agency

- Designed and developed bespoke WordPress websites using self-developed themes
- Developed web apps using HTML5, Sass / CSS3 and JavaScript along with React and Gatsby
- SEO, accessibility and performance optimisation of websites and web apps.

# London, UK

## 04/2014 - 12/2017

# Co-Founder & CTO, Immovato GmbH

- Developed a new way of selling and letting property in Germany along with my co-founder
- Managed a team of 2 full-stack developers working on the product (Angular in the front-end and Laravel in the back-end)
- Developed the design language, branding and UI of the product autonomously and developed MVP in HTML, Sass and JS

#### Wiesbaden, Germany

#### **Education**

I am self-tought from a young age and continuously strive to learn the latest technologies through online educational programmes and attending various conferences throughout the year.

#### 2019 - present

#### University of Helsinki - Full Stack Open

- Introduction to React
- Communicating with server
- Programming a server with NodeJS and Express
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Testing Express servers, user administration}\\$
- Testing React apps, custom hooks
- State management with Redux
- React router, styling apps with CSS and webpack
- GraphQL

# 2014 – 2019

#### **Treehouse Online Academy**

- Web Design
- WordPress Development
- PHP Development
- Front End Development
- Full Stack JavaScript
- React Development

#### Ranked 21 / 389k students

# Languages

- English (Native)
- German (Native)
- Spanish (B1)

- Italian (A2)
- Russian (A2)

# **Technical skills**

# Web Technologies and Frameworks

React JS, Gatsby, Next.js, HTML5, JavaScript (ES6), PHP, Node.js

# Styling

CSS3, Sass, Less, Styled Components, Bootstrap, Foundation

# **Databases & Data Structures**

MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, GraphQL, REST API / JSON

#### **Design Tools**

Adobe Illustrator, Adobe InDesign, Adobe Photoshop, Sketch

# **Content Management Systems**

Contentful, Sanity.io, WordPress, Drupal

# Versioning and other tools

Git, Github, Bitbucket, Docker, Jira, Yarn, NPM

# **Managerial skills**

- · Agile methodology
- Code optimisation
- Documentation & Reporting
- UI optimisation
- Team leadership
- Project management
- Client relationship management
- Stakeholder management
- Commercial awareness & On-time delivery
- Strong bi-lingual communication